Jed Lyle Fernandez

ϙ Metro Manila, Philippines 🖿 fernandezjedlyle@gmail.com 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/jed-lyle-fernandez-160239142/

SUMMARY

Experienced Game Developer with demonstrated experience in developing video game systems and tools, and leading cross functional teams. Strong knowledge of programming concepts and design patterns. Highly enthusiastic and willing to learn new systems in order to meet company needs.

EXPERIENCE

Team Lead, Senior Unity Developer

Narrasoft Inc.

July 2021 - Present, Mandaluyong, Philippines

- Outsourced to a game development startup in Tel Aviv, Israel called InnPlay Labs. I led a high performance team of up-to 5+ developers and technical artists, in the development and testing of games and its different features.
- · Architect and developed re-usable game systems and tools, allowing us to easily release multiple game titles with little-to-no developer intervention.
- · Coordinating with CTO, Technical Lead, and VP of R&D in mentoring other developers with feature planning and development. Ensuring that they meet the team's standards.
- · Leading the team to meet client expectations for code quality; completing code reviews to ensure that the code is reusable, performant, and readable.
- Conducting technical interviews and examinations for potential hires of the company.

Game Developer

NSTBG Philippines

October 2019 - June 2021, Taguig, Philippines

- · Coordinated with different departments in the development of different game features and systems.
- · Debugging and optimizing game systems.
- · Implementing third party Unity game libraries to speed up development of game projects.
- Developed in-house tools to streamline development and integration of game systems and assets using Google Docs, PlayFab, and Unity.

Software Engineer

Anino Inc.

September 2018 - October 2019, Makati, Philippines

- · Coordinate with Game Designers, Producers, and Quality Assurance in the development of new game systems and features.
- Debugging and optimizing existing game systems.
- Developed and maintained game tools for Game Designers, Quality Assurance, and Live Operations for modifying in–game data during server runtime.
- · Implementing in-game analytics for Game Designers and Quality Assurance to improve user experience and streamline investigation of issues.

Software Engineer Internship

Anino inc

August 2017 - March 2018, Makati, Philippines

- · Collaborated with Senior Developers, Game Designers, and Quality Assurance with development of in-game social features using the Unity game Engine.
- · Debugging and testing existing game systems.

PROJECTS

Tiles of Fortune

Narrasoft Inc. · September 2022 - Present

- · Assisting technical artists and other developers with integration of existing features, particularly ones that were mentioned in the Animal Kingdom: Coin Raid project.
- · Overseeing QA sessions with Technical Artists, other Developers, and other stakeholders. Filing any issues we find and determining which needs to be fixed or not.

Animal Kingdom: Coin Raid

Narrasoft Inc. • August 2021 - Present

- Developed several features and systems using the Unity Game Engine, PlayFab, Nakama Game Server, and AWS. I also dabbled in Vue and Node JS for developing web tools.
- · Developed and maintained a store rating system that allows the user to rate the game within the app using PlayFab and Unity.
- Developed and maintained a card system that has several sub features such as a randomized card chest, a joker card, and cards trading which increased user engagement and retention.

- Developed and maintained a cross platform mobile deep link system which we used in user acquisition efforts by rewarding users after installing the game or after redirecting them into the installed app.
- Extended the deep link system to also allow users to invite their friends outside of the app, rewarding host of the invite link which further increased user engagement and acquisition.
- Developed a web-based tool for generating deep links, so product and live operations can generate links without developer intervention. Developed the system using Vue and Node JavaScript.
- · Refactoring parts of the existing Unity codebase to be more generic and can easily be integrated with other features and games.
- · Overseeing QA sessions with Technical Artists, other Developers, and other stakeholders. Filing any issues we find and determining which needs to be fixed or not.

Murasaki7 - Anime Puzzle RPG

NSTBG Philippines · October 2019 - June 2021

- · Developed and maintained custom in-house Matchmaking system using Unity & PlayFab.
- \cdot Extend gameplay code to support PvP and integrating with the aforementioned matchmaking system.
- · Developed and maintained an audio system that uses Unity's Addressables system and dynamically load sound assets to prevent memory leaks.
- · Developed tools for Unity that parses Excel datasheets from Game Designers and converting them into in-engine data structures.
- Developed tools that allow Game Developers and Designers with mixing character audio, and streamlining localization for character voices within the Unity Game Engine.

Double Win Vegas

Anino Inc. · August 2017 - October 2019

- · Developed social game features such as a chat system and in-game social panel in order for players to interact with one another.
- Developed and maintained other existing game features such as a shop, club system, and social lobby. Improving the code base and overall performance.
- · Primarily developed in Unity but would dabble in Ruby on Rails and MongoDB to apply changes on the server-side.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology Major in Animation & Game Development

FEU - Institute of Technology · Sampaloc, Manila, Philippines · 2019

SKILLS

Game Development: C#, Unity, PlayFab, Nakama Game Server

Mobile Application Development: Kotlin, Swift

Web Servers: Go, JavaScript, Ruby, Docker, AWS, MongoDB

Web Development: JavaScript, HTML, CSS